well that's right ICICI Bank opened with
The Gap up today at 513 rupees um cooled
off slightly as the morning went on and
now it's back nearing the high point of
the day at 512 rupees now what happened
um and why is the stock moving upward
firstly it's playing catch up to kotak
bank and HDFC bank which have really
gone on to make new lifetime highs
postco for ICICI Bank it is yet to break
the threshold of its previous 52 week
high now in many respects it's just as
capable a bank it's one of the leading
private Banks it's got a great deposit
franchise which we now know is so
critical to any Bank success given that
um if you don't have a strong liability
franchise you simply don't have the fuel
to lend and um give your customers the
opportunity to grow their credit so ICA
bank is one that is sped um by many
brokerages to perform really well on
Friday they held an analyst day in which
they talked about the key aspirations
for the bank going forward and what the
road ahead might really look like so
we've summarized that for you here at ET
now and basically what it seems is that
there's going to be consistent growth in
deposits as well as the mobilization of
deposits and the granularity of deposits
second they're going to be looking at
capturing a better foothold in the
equity ecosystem also digital solutions
for branch transactions so all your
typical Branch transactions they now
want to be able to to enable their
customers to do all that digitally there
will be a healthy growth in the
protection space so credential Lombard
um of course the insurance subsidiaries
of IC Bank it seems that this business
is now going to be a focus area going
forward and they're looking to scale it
quite aggressively we then have
analytics that are going to be playing a
increasing role in credit decisions so
assessing a credit uh worthiness of a
potential new borrower or assessing
whether a borrower should should get an
enhanced limit or assessing what can be
cross- sold to a potential borrower so
can he be sold Insurance products or can
an insurance customer be sold something
within the banking portfolio that's a
same model that all large Western banks
have followed to really become large
financial institutions so that's going
to be more and more a theme at ICI
cross- selling is the term they use for
it then like I said earlier granularity
is going to be a focus area for the bank
to make sure that they are not too
dependent on any one single source of
deposits and that they're widespread
also on the credit side they'd want to
be more Diversified and not heavily
allocated to any specific sector um in
terms of what they've managed to achieve
in the last 3 years ICI bank has great
asset quality great asset and credit
growth of great operating profit growth
um they've also had very strong
liability build up right um so on all
fronts Bank performing really well um
retracing now towards that rather
climbing now to towards that 52- we high
and let's see maybe it'll catch up a
little more to uh the otherwise two
leaders in the sector kotak bank and
HDFC Bank